Zhao Huaijin.
How dare you kidnap an imperial official!
Let me go!
Tonight, I must sacrifice a living person
so I can send the Red Lady back to the underworld.
I was going to use a paper figure instead,
but I didn't expect you to deliver yourself to my door.
Tough luck for you.
What Red Lady?
You're clearly just playing tricks.
It was you.
You killed Chen Wenyuan and Liu Rumei.
You killed them!
Yes, I killed them!
I summoned the Red Lady
and let her kill that adulterous couple!
I succeeded!
What are you doing?
The auspicious hour has arrived.
Die!
The ghostly mist of the netherworld spreads,
demons guide the souls back.
Yin souls,
scatter to the yin coffins.
The ghostly mist of the netherworld spreads,
demons guide the souls back.
Yin souls,
return quickly to the yin coffins.
Yin souls, return quickly to the yin coffins.
How was it?
You did need me, didn't you?
Did you see that just now?
See what?
The Red Lady.
If she can't go back to the underworld,
we will all die.
It seems
Zhao Huaijin was scared out of his mind last night.
The Red Lady.
By the way,
yesterday
I found this in Zhao Huaijin's house.
The appearance and cause of death
are almost identical to those of Chen Wenyuan and Liu Rumei.
I read a book before
called 'Records of Wonders'.
The soul-summoning array in it
is exactly the same as the one in Zhao Huaijin's house.
Could it be
that ghosts really exist?
The Red Lady.
As for tales of ghosts and gods,
believe it and they exist, don't believe it and they don't.
Thank you for saving me yesterday.
So you do know how to say thank you.
Young master!
Something terrible has happened!
The Red Lady
has claimed another life!
The Red Lady.
This red thread technique
is exactly the same
as what was used on Chen Wenyuan and Liu Rumei.
What was the relationship
between the butler and Madam Liu?
They hooked up a long time ago.
Many people in the manor know about it.
Everyone just kept their mouths shut.
Last night,
what did you see?
I heard a noise in the mourning hall.
I saw the Red Lady
coming to take revenge on the Chen family.
What did you say?
The Red Lady has a grudge against the Chen family?
Yes.
Chen Wenyuan's father, Chen Sheng,
is the man who betrayed the Red Lady back then.
It turns out the unfaithful Chen Sheng has already died of illness.
The Red Lady kills people with red threads,
stitching the victims together,
driven by hatred.
The Red Lady's
original name was Lin Hongyuan.
Her lover Chen Sheng abandoned her,
so she became a vengeful spirit,
seeking revenge on his son, Chen Wenyuan.
She also killed Liu Rumei, who eloped with Chen Wenyuan.
The affair between Lin Hongyuan and Chen Sheng happened many years ago.
Why would she come out for revenge after all these years?
Purifying water,
canopy of the sun and moon,
Big Dipper hidden within,
three stars of inner yin,
departed souls return to the earth,
may the dead rest in peace.
Break!
The Red Lady has been released.
After investigation by our office,
the case of Chen Wenyuan and Liu Rumei
has been concluded
as an accident.
Over the next two days, let all the people in the city
properly pray for the Red Lady's release.
The case is closed.
My Lord.
There are many suspicious points in this case.
It cannot be closed yet.
Rumors are spreading all over the city.
Further investigation may cause trouble.
But...
Court dismissed.
Well?
Are we still investigating?
At Zhao Huaijin's house,
did you see it?
No.
I saw it.
It was very bizarre.
Then
let's investigate.
How about
telling your uncle?
Why tell him?
Tell me how you want to investigate,
and I'll help you.
You seem
not afraid of your uncle at all.
Afraid of him?
My mother is very powerful in Chang'an.
Lord Su,
I want to examine the bodies.
No.
The case is already closed.
The magistrate will be angry.
Suit yourselves.
Remember to lock the door.
Wait.
I want you to do the autopsy.
This...
Well?
Still afraid?
No problem.
I'll do my best.
You gave me so much.
I won't be able to pay you back.
You came just in time.
They are going to be buried tomorrow.
Have you found out the time of death?
Lord Su,
I found it.
The time of death should be that night.
Then the primary crime scene
was under the intertwined branches.
Do you have tweezers?
Yes.
Give me the limewater.
Here.
This isn't a red thread.
What is this?
A magnifying glass.
If I'm not mistaken,
this is ice silkworm silk from the Western Regions.
It has an extremely low temperature
and acts as a preservative.
Then the time of death would be much earlier.
At least three days.
It seems we need to expand our search area.
The crime scene
might be further away.
This ice silkworm silk is a rarity.
In Fangzhou,
there's only one place that might have it.
Lord Su.
After you.
Lord Su, Master Shen.